Inspired by true events.
The Two Popes is a drama, history film directed by Fernando Meirelles.
Frustrated with the direction of the church, Cardinal Bergoglio
requests permission to retire in 2012 from Pope Benedict.
Instead, facing scandal and self-doubt, the introspective Pope Benedict summons his harshest critic and future
successor to Rome to reveal a secret that would shake the foundations of the Catholic Church.
Jorge Bergoglio / Pope Francis, played by Jonathan Pryce.
Joseph Ratzinger / Pope Benedict XVI, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Young Jorge Bergoglio, played by Juan Minujín.
Cardinal Hummes, played by Luis Gnecco.
Lisabetta, played by Cristina Banegas.
Esther Ballestrine, played by María Ucedo.
The Two Popes is a 2019 biographical drama film directed by Fernando Meirelles and written by Anthony
McCarten, adapted from McCarten's play The Pope which premiered at Royal & Derngate Theatre in 2019.
Predominantly set in Vatican City in the aftermath of the Vatican leaks scandal, the film follows Pope Benedict XVI, played by Anthony Hopkins, as he attempts to convince Cardinal
Jorge Mario Bergoglio, played by Jonathan Pryce, to reconsider his decision to resign as an archbishop as he confides his own intentions to abdicate the papacy.
The film premiered at the Telluride Film Festival on August 31, 2019.
It began a limited theatrical release in the United States on November 27, 2019, and in the United
Kingdom on November 29, and started digital streaming on December 20, by Netflix.
The performances of Pryce and Hopkins, as well as McCarten's screenplay, received high praise from critics, and all three
received nominations for their work at the Academy Awards, Golden Globes and British Academy Film Awards.
The film explores themes of vatican (holy see), pope, based on
true story, catholic, roman catholic church.
The tone is emotional.